ANDRÉ IBARRA PÉREZ

Software Developer

⊠ ibarraandre98@gmail.com 🕿 +52 831 113 15 62 🐶 México ⊕https://ibarraandre98.github.io 🖼 barraandre

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 4 years of professional experience in native mobile applications using Android Studio (Kotlin and Java) and Ionic, as well as over a year of experience in FrontEnd Web development (Angular) and recently, half a year of experience using Laravel. Great analytical capacity to find solutions to the problems arise, responsibility, persistence, teamwork, self-taught, and a great ability to adapt quickly to changes, always seeking to achieve projects objectives efficiently, in addition staying up to date in software development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript - Typescript

PHP - Laravel

Android Studio - Kotlin/Java Ionic & Angular MySQL, SQLite

HTML - CSS

Supabase Firebase Git

English - Fluent Intermediate/Advanced Spanish - Native

LANGUAGES

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Android/Angular Developer, NEORIS

Feb 2021 - Present

- Developed various mobile applications for the following clients: OXXO, BBVA, FEMSA, CEMEX, ARCA CONTINENTAL.
- Development of an application with functionalities for home delivery of products, mobile top-ups, bank deposits, and bill payments. This has led to an increase in downloads and user retention, currently reaching 5 million downloads, as well as enhancing the user experience by reducing crashes by 90%.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to create high-quality applications that meet client demands, increase client retention, and thereby boost company profits.
- Implementation of user behavior analysis events, segmentation and functionalities capabilities, personalized messages per user, as well sending of push notifications using Amplitude, Leanplum, Facebook, Firebase and Salesforce (Interaction Studio, Marketing Cloud), Thus, enhancing the user experience by providing tailored information through product improvements.
- Worked under strict guidelines, following the SCRUM methodology, code documentation, daily code backups, clean code practices, and the use of design patterns.

Fullstack Developer, Duop (Freelance) May 2021 - Present

- Development from scratch of mobile applications, web applications, landing pages, databases, and APIs, meeting client needs, increasing productivity, and ensuring optimal user experience.
- Design, normalization, and creation of the database structure for an application with four types of users, managing test assignments, responses, result calculations through formulas, and PDF result generation, using Laravel.
- Developed an Ionic/Angular app for pool and villa rentals, with features for event management, exports, WhatsApp shortcuts, and search filters, increase in productivity and a 70% reduction in human error.
- Collaborated in developing an Angular web app for a towing service, implementing real-time service creation, push notifications with Socket IO, service feedback, and payment functionalities.

Web/Mobile Developer, Zangup

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021

- Developed an Angular web app with Angular Material and Firebase to showcase Squirk lubricant, including features like product reviews and forms for distribution or product issues.
- Designed and developed mobile applications using Ionic + Angular from scratch, initiated by Zangup for future resale to clients, with Firebase as the database.
- Created an Angular web app to manage a mobile app, sharing data through Firebase, with a UI layout based on UX designs and integrated with Bootstrap for responsive design.

EDUCATION

BUSINESS DOMAINS

Instituto Tecnológico Superior de El Mante 2016 - 2021 Computer Systems Engineering

Delivery Logistics

e-Commerce Retail

Distribution Financial Services